<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fedora on mhcerri: random notes</title>
    <link>https://mhcerri.github.io/tags/fedora/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fedora on mhcerri: random notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mhcerri at gmail dot com (Marcelo Henrique Cerri)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mhcerri at gmail dot com (Marcelo Henrique Cerri)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 09:11:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mhcerri.github.io/tags/fedora/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix load 1.0 issue on MK802</title>
      <link>https://mhcerri.github.io/posts/how-to-fix-load--issue-on-mk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 09:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mhcerri at gmail dot com (Marcelo Henrique Cerri)</author>
      <guid>https://mhcerri.github.io/posts/how-to-fix-load--issue-on-mk/</guid>
      <description>Note: I&amp;rsquo;m currently using a Raspberry Pi 2 and Arch Linux ARM
The load of my MK802 running Fedora 20 was constantly above 1.0. Checking the state of the processes I found:
$ ps -eo pid,state,cmd | awk &amp;#39;$2 != &amp;#34;S&amp;#34; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $2 != &amp;#34;R&amp;#34;&amp;#39; 34 D [usb-storage] After searching on Google, I found that it seems to be a problem related to the OTG port. To fix we need to change some parameters in the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini home server with MK802</title>
      <link>https://mhcerri.github.io/posts/mini-home-server-with-mk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 09:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mhcerri at gmail dot com (Marcelo Henrique Cerri)</author>
      <guid>https://mhcerri.github.io/posts/mini-home-server-with-mk/</guid>
      <description>Note: I&amp;rsquo;m currently using a Raspberry Pi 2 and Arch Linux ARM
My first attempt to set up a mini home server was using a Raspberry Pi as a torrent and a DLNA server running with an external HDD. Unfortunately it had a lot of USB related issues that caused the HDD and the network to disconnect very often. I tried several workarounds, from tweaks in the boot-loader to fixes in the kernel without success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Python from sources</title>
      <link>https://mhcerri.github.io/posts/installing-python-from-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 08:48:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mhcerri at gmail dot com (Marcelo Henrique Cerri)</author>
      <guid>https://mhcerri.github.io/posts/installing-python-from-sources/</guid>
      <description>Python is present in a large number of distros today and in fact most distros have at least one or more core components that are written or extensible using Python.
That is a good thing in the way that you can write Python application without any need to worry if Python will be available or not for ditro A or distro B. But it also creates some problems.
Not all python modules are available via the distro package manager There are thousands of modules and libraries available for Python, several of them are constantly updated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>